Kenneth A. Ferguson M.A.T

 $kenneth fergus on 90@gmail.com \infty (336) 840-8720 \infty$ Whitsett, NC 27377 LinkedIn:

<u>linkedin.com/in/kenneth-ferguson/</u> ∞ GitHub: <u>github.com/kferg357</u> Website: <u>https://kennethferguson.net</u>

Professional Summary

Full Stack Web Developer with 1 year of experience in Information Technology. Effective at combining creativity and problem solving to develop user-friendly applications. Have been known amongst staff for a strong wit and attention to detail regardless of complexity of the project, and recently earned a Certificate in Full Stack Web Development for The University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill.

TECHNICAL TOOLBOX

- Languages: HTML5, CSS, JAVA, JavaScript ES6+, SQL, NoSQL, React, Express
- Applications: GitHub, MongoDB, MySQL, Insomnia, Postman
- Tools: Node, Handlebars, Query, Bootstrap

PROJECTS

Daily Planner- Lead Developer- https://github.com/kferg357/Daily-Planner/ Planner.git Deployment- https://kferg357.github.io/Daily-Planner/

- A calendar application that allows a user to save events for each hour of the day
- Tools used: HTML and CSS HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, jQuery, Moment.js, JavaScript, Google API's

Note-Taker- Lead Developer- https://note-taker.git Deployment- https://note-taker.kferg357.herokuapp.com/

- An application that can be used to write and save notes.
- Tools Used: Express.js, Bootstrap, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, API's, HTTP Request methods

EXPERIENCE

Guilford County Schools Health and Physical Education Teacher

Greensboro, NC 06/2016-02/2021

- Communicate effectively with students, teachers, families and the school board.
- Asses and facilitate the strengths and needs of the "whole learner": physically, socially and emotionally moreover intellectually and academically.
- Stayed current with state and local standards for physical education curriculum, fitness, and nutrition expectations.
- Provided lessons that ensured maximum participation for all students; differentiated all lessons to improve students' success.

Guilford County Schools Remedial Teacher

Greensboro, NC 08/2012-06/2016

- Established and maintained positive relationships with students, parents, and colleagues, fostering an environment of open communication and support.
- Ensured classroom setting is conducive to a quality-learning environment and address disruptive issues in a concise and professional manner by following established procedures.
- Provides a continuum of prevention, intervention and treatment services for children and youth and their families who are at-risk, in crisis or who have emotional or behavioral problems.
- Focus on improving the communication, information-processing, problem-solving, and critical-thinking skills.

Guilford County Schools Teacher Assistant in Behavioral Classroom Setting

Greensboro, NC 08/2005-06/2011

- Worked as part of an interdisciplinary team to provide educational services to students who exhibit a variety of emotional and behavioral learning disabilities that impede their ability to function within a less restrictive classroom setting.
- Responsible for helping set curriculum plans and implementation procedures for teachers.
- Develop and implemented behavior management techniques to assist teachers with disruptive students.
- Assist students in improving academic and behavioral achievement by meeting with them on a regular basis to clarify learning problems and improve behavioral skills.
- Continuously strengthened professional and personal development by attending seminars and workshops for additional training.
- Served as Head 9th Grade Basketball Coach and Assistant Varsity Basketball Coach.

EDUCATION

The University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill Certificate in Full Stack Web Development

Chapel Hill, NC 03/2021-09/2021

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS

North Carolina A&T State University
Master of Arts in Teaching, Health and Physical Education (k- 12)

Greensboro, NC 2010-2012

North Carolina A&T State University Bachelor of Science., Fitness and Wellness Management Concentration in Business Administration Greensboro, NC 1999-2004